<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Miles Kodama</title>
    <link>https://mkodama.org/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Miles Kodama</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="https://mkodama.org/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Classical Mechanics</title>
      <link>https://mkodama.org/notes/class-mech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mkodama.org/notes/class-mech/</guid>
      <description>Motivation # So you&amp;rsquo;ve taken a first year college course on mechanics. You know Newton&amp;rsquo;s three laws by heart, and you can draw free body diagrams in your sleep. You might think that you know all there is to know about the behavior of large, dry, slow-moving objects, and in a certain sense, you do. Given the force laws and the initial conditions, you can in principle always crank out the state of the system numerically.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dirac Notation</title>
      <link>https://mkodama.org/notes/dirac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mkodama.org/notes/dirac/</guid>
      <description>This note is a stub for now—more soon!&#xA;Questions # What are the advantages of Dirac notation over the mathematicians&amp;rsquo; notation for inner product spaces? Reading List # Dirac&amp;rsquo;s original paper, &amp;ldquo;A new notation for quantum mechanics&amp;rdquo; ✔ Chapter 1 from Andre Lukas&amp;rsquo;s notes on mathematical methods for physicists ✔ Sakurai&amp;rsquo;s Modern Quantum Mechanics §1.2 Chapter 3 from Griffiths and Schroeter&amp;rsquo;s Intro to QM Hall, QT for Mathematicians §3.12 Last updated 5 September 2024</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dodgson Condensation</title>
      <link>https://mkodama.org/notes/dodgson-con/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mkodama.org/notes/dodgson-con/</guid>
      <description>The Reverend Charles Dodgson (alias Lewis Carroll) invented a neat method of taking determinants without cofactor expansion or row reduction. I like to think of his condensation method as building an imaginary pyramid of matrices. The base of the pyramid is the matrix whose determinant you&amp;rsquo;re trying to find. In the air above each of the base matrix&amp;rsquo;s interior whitespaces, you imagine writing the determinant of the two-by-two submatrix centered on that whitespace.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fuzzy Bayesianism</title>
      <link>https://mkodama.org/notes/fuzzy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mkodama.org/notes/fuzzy/</guid>
      <description>Clearly real humans do not have sharp credences on most propositions of real interest outside of games and scientific experiments. Perfectly sharp credences are ruled out by both our computational and our evidential constraints. Even if I could access enough evidence to pin down a unique sharp posterior on some realistic proposition, my brain runs too slowly to update on all this evidence in reasonable time, and it&amp;rsquo;s too small to hold the resulting infinitely precise credences in memory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measure Theory</title>
      <link>https://mkodama.org/notes/measures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mkodama.org/notes/measures/</guid>
      <description>A motivating example # Consider the function $f:[0,1]\to \mathbb{R}$ that takes all the irrational numbers to one and all the rational numbers to zero, ie&#xA;\[f(x) = \begin{cases}0 &amp;amp; x\in \mathbb{Q} \\ 1 &amp;amp; \text{otherwise}\end{cases}\]&#xA;If you try to graph this function in the plane, it looks like an equals sign. There&amp;rsquo;s a solid line of unit length going from (0,0) to (1,0) and another going from (0,1) to (1,1).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modal Realism</title>
      <link>https://mkodama.org/notes/modal-realism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mkodama.org/notes/modal-realism/</guid>
      <description>Some apparently sane philosophers believe that all possible worlds exist. In other words, they deny that real implies actual. Why would anyone believe this view, which is called modal realism?&#xA;(1) The most natural way of interpreting statements about chance is possibilist. Every claim about a chance is actually a claim about the distribution of possible worlds where some proposition is true. So when I say&#xA;The chance of event $E$ is $p$,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moral Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://mkodama.org/notes/moral-uncertainty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mkodama.org/notes/moral-uncertainty/</guid>
      <description>Maximizing Expected Choiceworthiness seems reasonable on its face, but I have three worries.&#xA;(1) I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that the best reasons we have to maximize expected value in cases of empirical uncertainty generalize to the case of moral uncertainty. For example, Law of Large Numbers arguments don&amp;rsquo;t apply if the event that you&amp;rsquo;re uncertain about is by its nature unrepeatable.&#xA;(2) It&amp;rsquo;s a very strict constraint on a moral theory to say it must rate all possible actions one might take with a single real number.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suffering-Focused Ethics</title>
      <link>https://mkodama.org/notes/sfe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mkodama.org/notes/sfe/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a cluster of ethical views that say the prevention of extreme suffering takes priority over all other goals. On some views, preference satisfaction, pleasure creation, and the like are still considered good, but suffering reduction takes lexical priority over them, or is at least so much more desirable that it crowds out these other goals in practice. Other suffering-focused views go further and deny that pleasure and preference satisfaction are good at all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Yankees Decision Problem</title>
      <link>https://mkodama.org/notes/yankees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mkodama.org/notes/yankees/</guid>
      <description>This scenario is supposed to counter the Why ain&amp;rsquo;cha rich? argument for EDT by showing that causalists can predictably out-earn evidentialists when faced with the right sort of game.&#xA;In Arntzenius&amp;rsquo;s original statement, the Red Sox and the Yankees are going to play a long series of games against each other, and it&amp;rsquo;s known that the Yankees have a 90% chance of winning each game. The (apparently ill-informed) oddsmakers are offering two bets on the games: a bet that pays out $1 if the Yankees win and loses $2 if the Red Sox win, and a bet that pays out $2 if the Red Sox win and loses $1 if the Yankees win.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
