<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Miles Kodama</title>
    <link>https://mkodama.org/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Miles Kodama</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="https://mkodama.org/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dodgson Condensation</title>
      <link>https://mkodama.org/notes/dodgson-con/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mkodama.org/notes/dodgson-con/</guid>
      <description>The Reverend Charles Dodgson (alias Lewis Carroll) invented a neat method of taking determinants without cofactor expansion or row reduction. I like to think of his condensation method as building an imaginary pyramid of matrices. The base of the pyramid is the matrix whose determinant you&amp;rsquo;re trying to find. In the air above each of the base matrix&amp;rsquo;s interior whitespaces, you imagine writing the determinant of the two-by-two submatrix centered on that whitespace.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moral Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://mkodama.org/notes/moral-uncertainty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mkodama.org/notes/moral-uncertainty/</guid>
      <description>Maximizing Expected Choiceworthiness seems reasonable on its face, but I have three worries.&#xA;(1) I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that the best reasons we have to maximize expected value in cases of empirical uncertainty generalize to the case of moral uncertainty. For example, Law of Large Numbers arguments don&amp;rsquo;t apply if the event that you&amp;rsquo;re uncertain about is by its nature unrepeatable.&#xA;(2) It&amp;rsquo;s a very strict constraint on a moral theory to say it must rate all possible actions one might take with a single real number.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Yankees Decision Problem</title>
      <link>https://mkodama.org/notes/yankees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mkodama.org/notes/yankees/</guid>
      <description>This scenario is supposed to counter the Why ain&amp;rsquo;cha rich? argument for EDT by showing that causalists can predictably out-earn evidentialists when faced with the right sort of game.&#xA;In Arntzenius&amp;rsquo;s original statement, the Red Sox and the Yankees are going to play a long series of games against each other, and it&amp;rsquo;s known that the Yankees have a 90% chance of winning each game. The (apparently ill-informed) oddsmakers are offering two bets on the games: a bet that pays out $1 if the Yankees win and loses $2 if the Red Sox win, and a bet that pays out $2 if the Red Sox win and loses $1 if the Yankees win.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
