<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Miles Kodama</title>
    <link>https://mkodama.org/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Miles Kodama</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mkodama.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Landmark Numbers</title>
      <link>https://mkodama.org/posts/numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mkodama.org/posts/numbers/</guid>
      <description>Motivation # You are awash in numbers. You read them in news articles, hear them in conversations, ponder over them in textbooks. The half-life of carbon 14 is 5700 years. The cruising speed of a Boeing 747 is 900 kilometers per hour. The diameter of a Covid-19 particle is 80 nanometers. Your response to this torrent of numbers could be to let it flow past without leaving much impression on your brain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let students use AI</title>
      <link>https://mkodama.org/posts/dunbar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mkodama.org/posts/dunbar/</guid>
      <description>I originally wrote this post for an essay contest at my school. It won the third place prize and was published in a campus magazine under a slightly different title. I&amp;rsquo;ll admit that my discussion is rather parochial in its focus on Williams, but my main claims easily generalize to other institutions. As always, I invite comments, objections, and feedback.&#xA;Williams is due for a deep rethink on the role of artificial intelligence (hereafter AI) in college classes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wear a nametag</title>
      <link>https://mkodama.org/posts/nametag/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mkodama.org/posts/nametag/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been wearing a nametag out in public (as often as I can remember to put it on) for the last three months, and I think you should consider doing the same. ⊕ Your nametag doesn’t have to be fancy. As you can see, mine isn’t. Why? # Remind acquaintances of your name. I have upwards of a hundred acquaintances I can recognize on sight and whom I&amp;rsquo;ve spoken to at least once whose names I cannot recall.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fooled by Randomness</title>
      <link>https://mkodama.org/posts/taleb-randomness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mkodama.org/posts/taleb-randomness/</guid>
      <description>Main points # I take this book to be mainly about the expected value (EV) principle, which says that when you make a decision under risk, you should maximize your probability weighted average payoff. The concept of expected value makes only a brief appearance in one chapter, and you won&amp;rsquo;t find a mathematical formula for it anywhere in the book. But as Taleb says, “mathematics is a tool to meditate, not compute,” and most of what he writes in Fooled by Randomness is implicitly a meditation on EV.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
